Hi, and welcome back to Living in
Central Texas. If you are looking for a
new and upandcoming community here in
the Temple Belton area, you'll want to
watch this video today as I give you a
tour of the Mesa Ridge community in
Temple, Texas, which is actually part of
Belton ISD. Hi, I'm Andrea Dudik,
realtor and associate broker with Vista
Real Estate. I'm so excited and grateful
to be here with you today. So, I am
standing in front of a Flint Rock home.
I will give you a tour of the inside
here in just a moment. As you can see,
it is a little windy today. We are, what
is it, March 12th, and it's extra
beautiful. Uh, temperature- wise though,
we're in the 70s. So, if you're curious
what the weather is like, uh, this is
it. and the the wind will come and go,
the weather will fluctuate some, but a
really beautiful march overall. In Mesa
Ridge Community, this is right off of
317 in Temple, which runs through Temple
and Belton. You're probably about 30
minutes from Fort Cavazos, about an hour
north of Austin, and about 40 to 45
minutes south of Waco, Texas. Being
right off of 317 makes this community
extra desirable because it makes getting
everywhere very easy. You're also very
close to West Adams, which is that main
road through Temple. um really amazing
restaurants, tons of shopping, coffee,
and so I really do think that this is a
hot community, especially falling in
Belton ISD, which we know is super
desirable. I thought it would be really
neat to take you along with me in my car
as we drive down West Adams, which is
that main road, main avenue through the
Temple Belt in the area with all of the
all of the best shopping and dining. uh
great access and I thought it would be
really helpful to see what that drive
looks like, what the area looks like,
and how quickly you get to Mesa
Ridge. Another really great feature
about this community is you have a
variety of builders. And so this home in
particular is priced just under 300,000
right now. And uh this builder, Flint
Rock, they have homes um just over that
here. I think going up to about
322,000 and they are
offering insane incentives, which they
do change. Um, but right now, as of
today, they're offering, I think, a
4.9% interest rate and a 21 buy down,
which if you're not sure what that is,
um, it is your first year is 2% less.
So, on that, your first year would be
three, I'm sorry, 2.9, your second year
would be 3.9, and then years 3 through
30 fixed are 4.9. Plus, they're paying
closing costs. And so in this moment in
time as of today, which again those can
change, really great opportunity to get
into a home like this for very little
money out of pocket, which is really
great. You also have some luxury homes
in this community on much larger lots,
you know, in the in the half million
price point by Kurthers. You also have
Omega in this community. um some smaller
builders
like Jerry Wright and uh DB Fuller. And
so I'll give you a tour of a Jerry
Wright home after we tour the Splint
Rock one. But uh really really great
variety of price points if you're
looking for a prime location, especially
if you know again that being a part of
Belton ISD and being right off of 317
and this easy access to everything is
important. you're at about a 2.3
property tax rate here. Uh property
taxes in Texas are a little bit higher
than a lot of other places. It's one of
the biggest I think misconceptions is
that while our home prices are somewhat
lower or much lower than a lot of other
areas. High school for for this
community is going to be Lake Belton
High School. Middle school will be North
Beltton Middle School. Um very close to
both of those, very close to parks and
walking trails. So again, this builder
is offering those really great
incentives. A lot of these other
builders are too. If you are interested
in the variety of builders and what
incentives they are currently offering,
you can always reach out to me. My
contact information is below. We can
have a chat. I can pull inventory for
you, see what we can negotiate for you.
Always make sure you have a realtor,
especially even with new construction.
So without further ado, let's take a
look at this Flint Rock home.
All right, so this first home is 8818
Trungle. It is the Flint Rock Blanco
floor plan, and I'd originally stated it
was about 290, but that is the same
floor plan just down the street. This
one is actually priced at
27190, which is, I'm pretty sure, the
lowest priced in this community.
And it is a three bed, two- bath home
with 1360 square ft. Built in 2024, but
it's brand new, never lived in. It has
an open floor plan which flows very seam
seamlessly between the living, dining,
and kitchen
areas. The kitchen has stainless steel
appliances, granite
countertops, and a spacious walk-in
pantry. I really, really love the light
fixtures in this home. This builder
always does a really great job with
their light fixtures and backsplash is
really pretty here, too. The main living
area has uh luxury vinyl plank flooring,
and all of the bedrooms are carpeted.
Very cool tones throughout this home.
Both bathrooms have granite countertops,
and the primary suite has a double
vanity and very nicely sized walk-in
shower. Outside, there's a small covered
patio, but full yard with sod and
irrigation and a 6 ft privacy fence,
which is great for hanging out outside
in Texas. Uh, something to be mindful of
whenever you are looking at new builds,
which is another reason to have a trusty
realtor is not all builders include
things like full saw and irrigation. And
there are actually numerous things that
you may think are included in a new
home, but are not. Again, this home is
super cute. Really ideal for a
first-time home buyer or someone looking
to retire.
I think this is a great investment
property in general just because this
area is so up and coming and location is
spot-on. Our second home is a Jerry
Wright home. This builder is just so
detailed and some things that they
typically do are going to be um their
wood beams and detailed ceilings.
This is a four bed, two bath home about
$18.90 square ft and it's priced at
[Music]
328. The kitchen is absolutely stunning.
Tons of counter space, very open to the
dining and living space.
It has tall custom cabinets, a large
corner walk-in pantry, stainless steel
appliances, and quartz
countertops. The beamed ceilings in the
living room add so much character, and
something that's really popular right
now is the durability of this ceramic
woodlook tile that that's throughout all
of the main living spaces, which is just
really great for durability and easy
maintenance.
[Music]
This builder also includes full yard
sod, a sprinkler system, a privacy
fence, a garage door opener, and faux
wood
blinds. They are offering insane
incentives as well, maxing out closing
costs, rate buy down, concessions, title
policy, survey. Again, all these things
can change daytoday, but right now they
are fantastic. Overall, you can just
really tell the detail that this builder
puts into his homes and the little
touches make all the difference in the
aesthetic and warmth of the
home. So, a little sideby-side
comparison. If you're looking for a more
affordable, well-designed home with a
cozy feel, the Flint Rock Blanco is a
fantastic option. But if you need a
little more space and love the idea of
very customized and detailed finishes,
this Jerry Wright home would be for you.
Both homes feature modern design,
beautiful finishes, great outdoor space,
um, and obviously that awesome location,
making them excellent choices for buyers
in central
Texas. Thanks for touring these two
beautiful builders here in the Mesa
Ridge community. If you would like any
more information on any of the others,
including their incentives and
inventory, you can find all my contact
information below. Don't forget to like
this video, subscribe, and click the
bell icon so that you can stay up to
date on all things real estate here in
Central Texas. Till next time.